# Gabriel De Almeida

Machello@gabrieldealmeida.com Regabrieldealmeida.com Regabedealmeida Peach, FLest Palm Beach, Flest P

# Summary

I'm a software engineer based in West Palm Beach, FL. I'm the co-founder of Campion ☑, an edge-based serverless middleware for implementing circuit-breaking functionality for distributed services. I have multiple years of experience with technologies across the entire stack, such as the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems, and cloud services such as AWS and Cloudflare. Previously, I founded a few companies in the tech industry, one of which, BooklyBox, was successfully acquired by Quarterly ♂.

### **Skills**

**Backend** Cloud Frontend **Tooling** Node.js, Express, Ruby, JavaScript (ES6), Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux AWS, Cloudflare, Digital Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, Ocean, Heroku MongoDB, RESTful APIs TailwindCSS, jQuery

## **Professional Experience**

2020 - present

## **Co-Founder, Software Engineer, Campion** 🖸

- Co-founded Campion, an edge-based serverless middleware for implementing circuitbreaking functionality for distributed services
- Built Campion to work on AWS and Cloudflare by using their SDK and API
- Resolved race conditions when incrementing failure/success counts by appending new entries to databases with unique time-based keys
- Designed Campion to work with all HTTP methods and to forward any incoming and outgoing headers and body
- Load tested Campion by using artillery.io to simulate 5,000+ concurrent requests
- Built an intuitive CLI and beautiful dashboard for users to track their metrics
- Collaborated daily with a fully remote team of engineers
- Co-authored Campion's case study: campion-breaker.github.io ☑

2018 - present

# Full-Stack Web Developer, Self Employed

- Dayllo: Trello-like app with React/Redux front-end and Ruby on Rails REST API backend
- Airline Routes: an interactive SVG map for viewing and filtering airline routes built with React and bootstrapped with Create React App
- Team Tickets: Ticket tracking app written in Ruby/Rails 6, PostgresSQL, deployed on Heroku

2017 - 2018

#### **Co-Founder, Growth Director, PageHabit**

- Led the growth team and grew our online book community to over 50,000 active members
- Created the influencer program to drive sustainable growth
- Implemented the one-for-one model to donate a book with every purchase

2015 - 2017

#### Founder, BooklyBox

- Founded BooklyBox, a monthly book membership with a thriving online community consisting of thousands of members
- Led a team of four employees and 15 moderators for our online community
- Acquired by Quarterly 
  ☐ in May of 2017

# **Education**